renfair.com 2019-06-11

# Privacy Policy - Renaissance Faire

##### Renaissance Entertainment Productions; the producers of the Renaissance Pleasure Faire, the Bristol Renaissance Faire, the New York Renaissance Faire and the Forest of Fear respect your right to privacy. Here’s what you may expect by utilizing our website, signing up for our newsletters, and purchasing tickets online:

## We do not share your information.

##### Renaissance Entertainment Productions utilizes Constant Contact to send emails to users who provide their email addresses with express consent. This information is only used while sending emails about Renaissance Entertainment Productions and is not shared by Renaissance Entertainment Productions with any further third parties. You can find Constant Contact’s privacy policy here: <https://www.endurance.com/privacy/privacy>

##### Renaissance Entertainment Productions utilizes ShowClix to process online ticket sales. Information collected during the order process is only used by ShowClix and Renaissance Entertainment Productions to provide the services you request and is not shared by Renaissance Entertainment Productions with any further third parties. Information is retained by Renaissance Entertainment Productions for no longer than seven years after you terminate services unless we are otherwise required by law or regulation to retain your personal information for longer. You can find ShowClix’s privacy policy here: <https://www.showclix.com/privacy-policy>

## The submission of your information is secure.

##### We use a secured server with an encrypted Secured Socket Layer (SSL) for the transmissions of your information. This protects you from those who would pirate your information.

## You are only signed up for the lists you choose.

##### If you wish to receive information for more of our events, you must subscribe to each one individually. You will only be contacted regarding the event(s) you’ve subscribed to.

## You are never forced to register for our mailings.

##### The only time you are required to give us your email address is during our online ordering process. This is so we may contact you about your order if necessary. We do not use these email addresses for our mailing list. To subscribe, you must use the subscription process.

## We do not send large volumes of mail.

##### We only send to postal addresses once or twice a year. Email newsletters can be as frequent as once a week while an event is in progress or if a deadline for a special offer is approaching. Otherwise, newsletters are sent every 1-2 months as appropriate to keep you informed of what is happening.

## You may unsubscribe at any time.

##### At the time of subscription, you will receive an email describing the unsubscribe process. Additionally, at the bottom of each email is a link to unsubscribe. You may also at any time simply reply to an email and ask to be removed. If you wish to re-subscribe, you are free to do so.

## We utilize a double opt-in method of subscription.

##### Once you have requested a subscription, our system will automatically send a confirmation email to the email address provided. This email will contain a URL that you will need to click on to confirm your subscription. You will then get a second email with the URL to unsubscribe.

### IP Addresses and Click-Stream Data

##### As is the case with many websites, our servers automatically collect your IP address when you visit our Site, and we may associate that with your domain name or that of your Internet access provider. We may also capture certain “clickstream data” pertaining to your Site usage. Clickstream data includes, for example, information about your computer or device, web browser and operating system and their settings, the referring page that linked you to the Site, the pages, content or ads you see or click on during your visit and when and for how long you do so, items you download, the next website you visit when you leave the Site, and any search terms you have entered on the Site or a referral site.

### Cookie Policy of renfair.com

##### Cookies are small data files stored on your computer or device at the request of a Web site. A cookie assigns a unique numerical identifier to your Web browser, and may enable us to recognize you as the same user who was at our Site in the past, and relate your use of the Site to other information about you, such as your Site usage information and personal information. Cookies may also be used to enhance your experience on the Site (for example, by storing your username so you can log in easily, keeping you logged into the Site after you have provided your password, and storing the contents of your shopping cart as you browse) or to collect general usage and aggregated statistical information and detect and prevent fraud. Most browsers can be set to detect cookies and give you an opportunity to reject them, but refusing cookies may, in some cases, inhibit or preclude your use of the Site or its features.  
Where the installation of Cookies is based on consent, such consent can be freely withdrawn at any time following the instructions provided in this document.

### Technical Cookies and Cookies serving aggregated statistical purposes

### Activity strictly necessary for the functioning of the Service

##### This Application uses Cookies to save the User’s session and to carry out other activities that are strictly necessary for the operation of this Application, for example in relation to the distribution of traffic.

### Activity regarding the saving of preferences, optimization, and statistics

##### This Application uses Cookies to save browsing preferences and to optimize the User’s browsing experience. Among these Cookies are, for example, those used for the setting of language and currency preferences or for the management of first party statistics employed directly by the Owner of the site.

### Other types of Cookies or third parties that install Cookies

##### Some of the services listed below collect statistics in an anonymized and aggregated form and may not require the consent of the User or may be managed directly by the Owner – depending on how they are described – without the help of third parties.  
If any third party operated services are listed among the tools below, these may be used to track Users’ browsing habits – in addition to the information specified herein and without the Owner’s knowledge. Please refer to the privacy policy of the listed services for detailed information.

### Analytics

##### The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Google Analytics (Google Inc.)

##### Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

##### Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.  
Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

### How to provide or withdraw consent to the installation of Cookies

##### In addition to what is specified in this document, the User can manage preferences for Cookies directly from within their own browser and prevent – for example – third parties from installing Cookies.  
Through browser preferences, it is also possible to delete Cookies installed in the past, including the Cookies that may have saved the initial consent for the installation of Cookies by this website.  
Users can, for example, find information about how to manage Cookies in the most commonly used browsers at the following addresses: [Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en&p=cpn_cookies), [Mozilla Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences), [Apple Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411) and [Microsoft Internet Explorer](http://windows.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-vista/block-or-allow-cookies).

##### Regarding Cookies installed by third parties, Users can manage their preferences and withdrawal of their consent by clicking the related opt-out link (if provided), by using the means provided in the third party’s privacy policy, or by contacting the third party.

##### Notwithstanding the above, the Owner informs that Users may follow the instructions provided on the subsequently linked initiatives by the [EDAA](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) (EU), the [Network Advertising Initiative](https://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-digital-advertising) (US) and the [Digital Advertising Alliance](https://www.aboutads.info/consumers/) (US), [DAAC](https://youradchoices.ca/understanding-online-advertising/) (Canada), [DDAI](http://www.ddai.info/optout) (Japan) or other similar services. Such initiatives allow Users to select their tracking preferences for most of the advertising tools. The Owner thus recommends that Users make use of these resources in addition to the information provided in this document.

### Owner and Data Controller

##### Renaissance Entertainment Productions  
357 McCaslin Blvd Suite 200  
Louisville, CO 80027  
United States

#### Owner contact email: webmaster@renfair.com

##### Since the installation of third-party Cookies and other tracking systems through the services used within this Application cannot be technically controlled by the Owner, any specific references to Cookies and tracking systems installed by third parties are to be considered indicative. To obtain complete information, the User is kindly requested to consult the privacy policy for the respective third-party services listed in this document.

##### Given the objective complexity surrounding the identification of technologies based on Cookies, Users are encouraged to contact the Owner should they wish to receive any further information on the use of Cookies by this Application.

### Third Party Ad Servers and Networks

##### We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Site or to serve our ads on third-party Web sites. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other Web sites, the region of the country or world where your IP address indicates you are located, as well as other information about you in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. These advertisements may appear on this Site and on other Web sites. These companies may employ cookies, clear GIFs and other tracking technologies to cause relevant ads to be displayed to you. We encourage you to read these businesses’ privacy policies to learn about how they treat your information.

##### Administrative or Legal Process: We or others may disclose your personal information to third parties without notice to you in order to comply with applicable law, law enforcement agencies, to protect our or third parties’ rights, or to protect the rights of other users of the Site.

### SOCIAL NETWORKING

##### We maintain a presence on several social networking and blogging platforms, such as Facebook and Twitter, and we also incorporate some third party social networking features onto our Site. Through these platforms and features, we receive some personal information and some Site usage information about you, and this Privacy Policy applies to that information as well. We may also include tools on our Site that allow you to share and/or publicly post content or information from our Site to your profile on a third party social network. Third party social networking platforms and blogging platforms have their own privacy policies which explain how they will use, protect and share your information, including any information you share on those platforms from our Site, and we encourage you to read them.

### HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION COLLECTED

##### We own the information collected on or through the Site. As applicable, the information you provide to us may be used by us or our service providers to:

  * ##### contact you about the Site;

  * ##### provide you with services or information you have requested or products or services you have registered for or other products and services;

  * ##### contact you regarding a specific product of interest;

  * ##### contact you regarding future product offerings;

  * ##### monitor or improve the use of the Site;

  * ##### market research;

  * ##### monitor compliance with our terms and conditions of use of the Site;

  * ##### process and fulfil your transactions;

  * ##### send you promotional material or special offers of ours, our other marketing partners, licensed sales agents and/or their respective affiliates and subsidiaries and other third parties;

  * ##### protecting our rights and property;

  * ##### recovering debt and preventing fraud;

  * ##### customizing our Site to your interests and history with us;

  * ##### tailoring ads displayed to you on our Site and elsewhere to your interests and history with us; and

  * ##### other purposes disclosed when personal information is submitted to us.

##### To perform the above functions, we may match information collected from you through different means or at different times, including both personal information and Site usage information, and use such information along with information obtained from other sources (including third parties) such as demographic information and updated contact information. We or our service providers may also use your information to assess the level of interest in, and use of, the Site, our e-mails and our other messaging campaigns both on an individual basis and in the aggregate.

### Definitions and legal references

#### Personal Data (or Data)

##### Any information that directly, indirectly, or in connection with other information — including a personal identification number — allows for the identification or identifiability of a natural person.

#### Usage Data

##### Information collected automatically through this Application (or third-party services employed in this Application), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use this Application, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server’s answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User’s IT environment.

#### User

##### The individual using this Application who, unless otherwise specified, coincides with the Data Subject.

#### Data Subject

##### The natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)

##### The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes Personal Data on behalf of the Controller, as described in this privacy policy.

#### Data Controller (or Owner)

##### The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Application. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of this Application.

#### This Application

##### How the Personal Data of the User is collected and processed.

#### Service

##### The service provided by this Application as described in the relative terms (if available) and on this site/application.

#### European Union (or EU)

##### Unless otherwise specified, all references made within this document to the European Union include all current member states to the European Union and the European Economic Area.

#### Cookies

##### Small piece of data stored in the User’s device.

#### Legal information

##### This privacy statement has been prepared based on provisions of multiple legislations, including Art. 13/14 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (General Data Protection Regulation).

##### This privacy policy relates solely to this Application, if not stated otherwise within this document.
